{
    "questions": [
    {
        "question": "Liyaqat Ali",
        "correctAnswer": "Allahabad",
        "explanation": " Allaha Liya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Devi Singh",
        "correctAnswer": "Mathura",
        "explanation": " + - * Math Devi "
    },
    {
        "question": "Kadam Singh",
        "correctAnswer": "Meerut",
        "explanation": " #Mee rat Kadam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maulvi Mohammed Ullah",
        "correctAnswer": "Faizabad",
        "explanation": " "
    },
    {
        "question": "Khan Bahadur",
        "correctAnswer": "Bareilly",
        "explanation": " "
    },
    {
        "question": "Rao Tula Ram",
        "correctAnswer": "Haryana",
        "explanation": " "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nawab Ali Bahadur",
        "correctAnswer": "Banda",
        "explanation": " "
    },
    {
        "question": "Begam Hazrat Mahal",
        "correctAnswer": "Lucknow",
        "explanation": " Declared BIRJIS KADIR as Nawab. Campbell came with Gurkhas and regained lucknow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nana Saheb",
        "correctAnswer": "Kanpur",
        "explanation": " Peshwa, Kanpur. Tatya tope helped him"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tatya Tope",
        "correctAnswer": "Kanpur",
        "explanation": " "
    },
    {
        "question": "Kunwar Singh",
        "correctAnswer": "Bihar",
        "explanation": "Jagdishpur, Bihar - From Shahabad District"
    },
    {
        "question": "Deewan Maniram Dutt",
        "correctAnswer": "Assam",
        "explanation": "Declared KAMDPESHWAR SINGH as king"
    },
    {
        "question": "Maulvi Ahmadullah Shah",
        "correctAnswer": "Faizabad",
        "explanation": " Faizabad 1857"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mutiny started in",
        "correctAnswer": "Meerut",
        "explanation": "On <b> 10 May 1857 </b>"
    }
],
"states": ["Allahabad","Mathura","Meerut","Faizabad","Bareilly","Haryana","Banda","Auwa","Marwar","Lucknow","Kanpur","Bihar","Assam","Jhansi"]
}